<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Diptanuj Sarkar</title>
    <link>https://casiowave.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Diptanuj Sarkar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://casiowave.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Ethics of Belief, William K. Clifford</title>
      <link>https://casiowave.github.io/interests/philosophy/the-ethics-of-belief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://casiowave.github.io/interests/philosophy/the-ethics-of-belief/</guid>
      <description>Reading at the Mohanpur Circle. Deals with the question: Is it always wrong to hold a belief without proper justification?</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The original text: <a href="https://people.brandeis.edu/~teuber/Clifford_ethics.pdf">The Ethics of Belief</a>
Relevant SEP page: <a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/ethics-belief">Ethics of Belief</a></p>
<h2 id="11012025">[11/01/2025]</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Brackets are used to express questions that arise in my mind while reading the text.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Clifford relays a story to motivate his claims:
A shipowner is going to sell tickets for a transatlantic journey. He gets doubts (they are possibly presented to him, with/without evidence) that the ship is not seaworthy. The shipowner is initially unhappy but does not investigate any further and manages to acquire a “sincere and comfortable conviction” that the vessel is safe. He sells the tickets, the ship sails and then sinks, and he collects the insurance money.</p>
<p>Clifford claims:</p>
<ul>
<li>The shipowner is guilty of the deaths of those on the ship.</li>
<li>The shipowner may have been sincerely convinced (note: is this even possible?) of the seaworthiness of the ship, but he is still in the “wrong” (assumed to be a moral wrong) because “<strong>he had no right to believe on such evidence as was before him</strong>”<strong>.</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>How does Clifford justify this?</p>
<ul>
<li>He had not earned the belief by patient investigation of evidence.</li>
<li>He had knowingly worked himself into the state of mind where he believed in the seaworthiness.</li>
</ul>
<p>Thus, he must be held responsible for the “wrongness” of his belief.</p>
<p>Clifford alters the story, imagining an outcome where the journey is completed safely. He claims that <strong>even in this case, the shipowner is in the wrong</strong>.
Why?</p>
<ul>
<li>Clifford says that action once carried out is either right or wrong forever. No outcome, good or evil, can change that.</li>
<li>The shipowner in this case was not right, he just wasn’t found out and saved by sheer accident.</li>
</ul>
<p>In summary, Clifford believes that <strong>it does not matter if a belief turns out to be true or false, but whether the person holding said belief had a right to believe on such evidence as was before them</strong>.</p>
<p>Another story:
A group of people are professing a religion that goes against some predominant religious notions on some islands. Those not part of this newer religion have a suspicion that those involved with it are using unfair and unethical (?) means to preach to children. In response, a group formed and they published grave accusations against the people involved with the new religion, <em>without investigating their claims</em>. A commission is formed to investigate them, and the accusations are found to be entirely false.</p>
<p>Clifford uses this to make the same claim as in the story before.</p>
<p>He addresses a doubt - we may say that it is not the belief that is in the wrong, but the action following upon it.</p>
<ul>
<li>The shipowner may say, “I am certain that the ship is safe, but it is my duty to have her examined”.</li>
<li>The agitators may be told, “You may be convinced of your allegations, but you ought not to have made a public attack without investigating them further”.</li>
</ul>
<p>Clifford admits that this view is <em>right</em> and <em>necessary</em>,</p>
<ul>
<li>Why right? Even with fixed belief, a person always has a choice regarding any action suggested by the belief. Thus, they have the responsibility to test their convictions.</li>
<li>Why necessary? “Those who are not yet capable of controlling their feelings and thoughts must have a plain rule dealing with overt acts”. (What does this mean? Who are the people “not capable” of said control? What “overt act”?)</li>
</ul>
<p>He points out that the view is <em>not sufficient</em> (clear from the fact that he calls it necessary), and that we require his previous claim (of there being no right to believe on insufficient evidence) to supplement this view.
He claims that,</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>It is not possible to sever the belief from the action it suggests.</strong> Thus, we can not condemn one without condemning the other.</li>
</ul>
<p>Why? He reasons that a person who believes in (or, is even inclined towards) one side of an argument/question may never be able to investigate it with the fairness and completeness of someone who has no such bias.
(Is it true that our biases are <em>always</em> stronger than our belief in the process of proper investigation?)
He goes ahead and makes a stronger claim: <strong>A belief that does not have any influence on the actions of the person who holds it is not a true belief.</strong>
(Then what is a belief that does not inspire action? Say, I have a belief that includes that clause that says if I ever act in a way that lets others know of said belief, I would be committing a wrong deed. Is such a thought not a belief for Clifford, or is he contesting that such a thought simply can not exist?)
He claims that,</p>
<ul>
<li>Any person who has ever wanted to commit an action inspired by some belief has “already committed it in his heart”. (How can committing something “in the heart” equivalent in anyway to real action?)</li>
<li>If a belief is not immediately causing a real action, it is “stored away” to influence future actions - it goes into some part of our minds, made up of an aggregate of beliefs, that is the link between sensation and action at all moments of our lives (So, are all of our actions motivated by a belief or some remnant of it? Are there no actions not motivated by beliefs?)
<ul>
<li>Further, he claims that this “aggregate” can not be separated into the constituent beliefs, and each new belief inducted into it changes its structure.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>So, every belief (true belief, as he defines it) is linked to some action, ultimately. Not only that, but each belief opens us up to more similar beliefs.</li>
</ul>
<p>As a result, Clifford argues that no person may have something akin to a “private belief”. This, combined with the claim that humans live in societies where we have shared, common heritage, leads him to draw the conclusion that any belief (no matter how trivial) has far reaching consequences. So, he extends his judgement to all beliefs held by all sorts of people, and claims that individuals have to earn their beliefs by examination because they hold these beliefs for all of humanity.</p>
<p>He acknowledges that the burden of such thorough examination of ourr beliefs is a heavy one, and reasons that this is not only because of the difficulty in carrying out such examination but also because we feel safe and secure in holding a fixed belief whereas doubting it makes us bare and powerless. <strong>This sense of power attached to believing is what makes people desirous of believing, and afraid of doubting</strong>.
He argues that we should earn said power through our examination of evidence instead of resorting to a fake sense of power - as justified belief enriches not just the individual holding the belief but also mankind as a whole.
Additionally, he claims that unjustified belief not only runs the risk (or, in his view the certainty) of wrong action, but it also encourages others to belief without justification. This perpetuates the problems of unjustified belief. On the other hand, a person who seeks evidence for or against his belief inspires a similar spirit of inquiry in others, thereby making mankind more virtuous.
Thus, he states his principle -
<strong>It is wrong always, everywhere, and for anyone, to believe anything upon insufficient evidence.</strong>
He proceeds next to make an every stronger statement, saying that once inquiry has been completed to the greatest extent possible and a belief accepted, <strong>it is still the duty of every person holding a belief to continue to be open to evidence for or against the belief.</strong>
(Is he not ccontradicting himself? If the belief is accepted as justified at some point in time, is the person holding the belief not “biased” as he puts it before - and thereby incapable of a fair assessment of further evidence? So, does belief-acceptance bar a person from belief-relinquishment?)
He finishes the section by saying that a person who does not have the time for such inquiry should not have the time to believe.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barchan Dunes interacting with Obstacles</title>
      <link>https://casiowave.github.io/physics/barchan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://casiowave.github.io/physics/barchan/</guid>
      <description>Summer Research Project that I carried out under Prof. Rajesh Ganapathy at JNCASR, Bengaluru</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here is the project report for the Project on Barchan Dunes that I carried out under the SRFP (Summer Research Fellowship Program) of the Indian Academy of Sciences, in the Summer of 2024.</p>
<div id="adobe-dc-view" style="height: 1000px"></div>

<script src="https://acrobatservices.adobe.com/view-sdk/viewer.js"></script>

<script type="text/javascript">
    document.addEventListener("adobe_dc_view_sdk.ready", function () {
        var adobeDCView = new AdobeDC.View({
            clientId: "c82825ed4f584af9ab27434556c33d08",
            divId: "adobe-dc-view",
        });

        adobeDCView.previewFile({
            content: {
                location: {
                    url: "https://casiowave.github.io/pdf/without-code.pdf",
                },
            },

            metaData: { fileName: "without-code.pdf" },
        });
    });
</script>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semester 4</title>
      <link>https://casiowave.github.io/notes/2024/02/semester-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://casiowave.github.io/notes/2024/02/semester-4/</guid>
      <description>Good Luck</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>You can find all the notes (incomplete ones and lab notes included) uploaded here - <a href="https://github.com/CasioWave/Lecture-Notes/tree/main/Sem%204">link</a></p>
<h2 id="end-semester-merged-notes">End Semester Merged Notes</h2>
<p>Only these are complete -</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/pdf/ph2201-endsem.pdf">PH2201: Basic Quantum Mechanics</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="mid-semester-merged-notes">Mid Semester Merged Notes</h2>
<p>I only have these notes complete, here they are -</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/pdf/qmech-midsem-merge.pdf">PH2201: Basic Quantum Mechanics</a></li>
<li><a href="/pdf/thermal-midsem-merge.pdf">PH2202: Thermal Physics</a></li>
<li><a href="https://thepiedpieper.github.io/notes/">Adrika&rsquo;s Notes for LS2202</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="typed-up-notes">Typed up notes</h2>
<p>These will only be updated until I realise I should just <em>stop</em> and study Analysis instead (I need to pass).</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/pdf/PH2202-typ.pdf">PH2202: Thermal Physics</a></li>
<li><a href="/pdf/PH2201-typ.pdf">PH2201: Basic Quantum Mechanics</a></li>
</ul>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://i.pinimg.com/originals/12/85/f9/1285f940365ae756e7ad8627511ff82c.gif" alt="cinco de mayo"  /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Physics Links</title>
      <link>https://casiowave.github.io/physics/interesting-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://casiowave.github.io/physics/interesting-links/</guid>
      <description>Some interesting links from around the internet</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I plan on collecting all the cool sites that I find, related to Physics of course, here.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://kirkmcd.princeton.edu/examples/">K. McDonald&rsquo;s Physics Examples</a>: A rich, old-internet site with myriad resources pertaining to physics.</li>
<li><a href="https://physics.stackexchange.com/questions/12175/resource-recommendations">PSE: Book Recommendations</a>: Physics StackExhange&rsquo;s very own list of recommended books and resources.</li>
<li><a href="https://telescoper.blog/category/cute-problems/">In The Dark: Cute Problems</a>: A very nice little blog with some nice questions.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.damtp.cam.ac.uk/user/tong/teaching.html">Tong Lectures</a>: The David Tong lecture notes.</li>
<li><a href="https://scienceworld.wolfram.com/">Wolfram ScienceWorld</a>: A cool website with a lot of historical information.</li>
<li><a href="https://quantummechanics.ucsd.edu/ph130a/130_notes/130_notes.html">UCSD Quantum Mechanics Notes</a>: Equation heavy, but thorough Quantum Mechanics notes.</li>
<li><a href="https://ocw.mit.edu/search/?d=Physics">MIT OCW Physics</a>: Of course</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semester 3</title>
      <link>https://casiowave.github.io/notes/2024/01/semester-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://casiowave.github.io/notes/2024/01/semester-3/</guid>
      <description>Some lecture notes from Semester 3</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here are some of the lectures notes that I took in Semester 3.</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="/pdf/PH2101.pdf">PH2101: Waves and Oscillations</a> (Credits to Adrika and Piyush for filling in the parts that I missed)</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euler-Lagrange equations: A derivation</title>
      <link>https://casiowave.github.io/physics/euler-lagrange/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://casiowave.github.io/physics/euler-lagrange/</guid>
      <description>This is me trying out KaTeX on the site</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="introduction">Introduction</h1>
<p>We start off by taking as a prototype the simple Newtonian scheme of a point particle of mass $m$ moving along the x-axis under a potential field $V(x)$.</p>
<p>According to Newton&rsquo;s Second Law of motion,
$$
m \frac{d^2 x}{dt^2} = - \frac{dV}{dx}
$$</p>
<p>If we are given the position and the velocity of this particle at some initial time, i.e. $x(t_i)$ and $\dot{x}(t_i)$, then it is possible for us to compute the classical trajectory of the particle $x_{cl}(t)$ as follows
$$
x_{cl}(t+\Delta t) = x(t_i) + \dot{x}(t_i) \Delta t
$$</p>
<p>We can keep following the same iteration scheme to calculate the position at $t+2\Delta t$, $t+3\Delta t$, and so on.</p>
<p>Since the equation of motion is second order in time, there are two pieces of data (namely, $x(t_i)$ and $\dot{x}(t_i)$) that are required to specify a unique $x_{cl}(t)$. An equivalent way to doing the same thing is to specify an initial point $(x_i,t_i)$ and a final point $(x_f,t_f)$ (Why?).</p>
<p>In the Lagrangian formalism, the same problem is posed in this way: <strong>Given the initial and the final point, what is it that distinguishes the actual classical trajectory joining these point from the infinite other trajectories that join these two points?</strong>
The answer to this lies in the following points:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Define a function $\mathbf{L}$, called the <strong>Lagrangian</strong> which is given by,
$$
\mathbf{L} = T - V
$$
$T$ and $V$ being the kinetic and potential energies of the particle.
Thus, $\mathbf{L} = \mathbf{L}(x,\dot{x})$. Note that we assume the absence of $t$ dependence by considering a potential field that is not time-dependent.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For each path $x(t)$ connecting $(x_i,t_i)$ and $(x_f,t_f)$, calculate the <strong>action</strong>, defined by,
$$
S[x(t)] = \int_{t_i}^{t_f} \mathbf{L}(x,\dot{x}) dt
$$
There are square brackets because we want to remember that the argument of S is the <strong>entire path</strong> or the <strong>entire function</strong> $x(t)$, not just the value of the function at some time. $S$ is thus also called a <strong>functional</strong>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Principle of Least Action</strong>: The classical path is the one on which $S$ is a <em>minimum</em> (Actually, it is only required that it be an extremum. The name is merely customary).</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, we verify whether this principle gives us back Newton&rsquo;s Second Law.</p>
<h2 id="a-multivariable-detour">A multivariable detour</h2>
<p>Since $S$ is a function of some other function $x(t)$, it is really just a multivariable function of $n$ variables as $n\rightarrow \infty$.
This is due to the fact that the function $x(t)$ actually specifies an infinite number of values $x(t_i), \dots , x(t) , \dots , x(t_f)$ - one for each instant in time $t$ in the specified interval.
We will deal with the entire minimum (actually, extremum) situation of the action by generalising how we deal with it in n variables.
Let us define a function,
$$
f = f(x_1, \dots , x_n) = f(\vec{x})
$$
The minimum of this function, say, $\vec{x^0}$ is characterised by the fact that if we move away from it by a small amount $\vec{\eta}$ in any direction, the first order change in $f$ vanishes.
Using the Taylor expansion,
$$
f(\vec{x^0}+\vec{\eta}) = f(\vec{x^0}) + \sum_{i=1}^{n} \frac{\partial f}{\partial x_i} \bigg\rvert_{\vec{x^0}} \eta_i + \text{ higher order terms in } \eta
$$
then, we get,
$$
\delta f^{(1)} = \sum_{i=1}^{n} \frac{\partial f}{\partial x_i} \bigg\rvert_{\vec{x^0}} \eta_i = 0
$$
as <strong>the first order change vanishes</strong>.
From this, we can see that if we choose $\vec{\eta}$ such that it is along the ith direction, <strong>every first order partial derivative of the function vanishes at</strong> $\vec{x^0}$.
$$
\frac{\partial f}{\partial x_i} \bigg\rvert_{\vec{x^0}} = 0 \quad , i = 1,\dots , n
$$</p>
<h2 id="coming-back-to-the-action">Coming back to the action</h2>
<p>We now use the property that we deduced to arrive at the extremum of $S$. We assume that $x_{cl}(t)$ is the path of least action (as per the principle), and that $x_{cl}(t) + \eta(t)$ is a &ldquo;nearby&rdquo; path.
As all the paths have to coincide at the initial and the final points, we get the condition,
$$
\eta(t_i) = \eta(t_f) = 0
$$
So now we get to the main attraction,
$$
S[x_{cl}(t) + \eta(t)] = \int_{t_i}^{t_f} \mathbf{L} (x_{cl}(t) + \eta(t),\dot{x}_{cl}(t) + \dot{\eta}(t)) dt
$$</p>
<p>Now, expanding the Lagrangian to its Taylor series expression,</p>
<p>$$
\Rightarrow S[x_{cl}(t) + \eta(t)] = \int_{t_i}^{t_f} \bigg[ \mathbf{L} ( x_{cl}(t), \dot{x}_{cl}(t) ) + \frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial x(t)} \bigg \vert _{x _{cl} } \cdot \eta(t) + \frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial \dot{x}(t)} \bigg \vert _{x _{cl} } \cdot \dot{\eta}(t) + \cdots \bigg] dt
$$</p>
<p>$$
\Rightarrow S[x_{cl}(t) + \eta(t)] = S[x_{cl}(t)] + \delta S^{(1)} + \text{ higher order terms }
$$
Since this is the case with infinite variables, the sum involving the first order partial derivatives of the action has been converted into an integral.
Using the fact that we deduced earlier regarding the first order change going to zero, we can say,
$$
0 = \delta S^{(1)} = \bigg[ \frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial x(t)} \bigg \vert _{x _{cl} } \cdot \eta(t) + \frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial \dot{x}(t)} \bigg \vert _{x _{cl} } \cdot \dot{\eta}(t) \bigg] dt
$$
If we integrate the second term by parts with the partial derivative as the first function and the $\dot{\eta}$ term as the second function (Why? It has $\dot{\eta}(t)$, and we know that $\eta$ cancels out at the ends) we get:
$$
\frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial \dot{x}(t)} \bigg \vert _{x _{cl} } \cdot \eta(t) \bigg \vert _{t_i}^{t_f} - \int _{t_i} ^{t_f} \bigg[ \frac{d}{dt} \frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial \dot{x}(t)} \bigg] _{x _{cl} } \cdot \eta(t) dt
$$
As mentioned before, the first term here vanishes.
So, we get:
$$
0 = \delta S^{(1)} = \int _{t_i} ^{t_f} \bigg[ \frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial x(t)} - \frac{d}{dt} \frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial \dot{x}(t)} \bigg] _{ x _{cl} } \cdot \eta(t) dt
$$
Here, the integral and the stuff inside the bracket acts like the infinite analogue of the sum of all the first order partial derivatives of the multivariable function, i.e. the discrete variable $\eta$ is replaced by $\eta(t)$, the sum over $i$ is replaced by the integral over &amp;t&amp;, and $\frac{\partial f}{\partial x_i}$ is replaced by $\frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial x(t)} - \frac{d}{dt} \frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial \dot{x}(t)}$.
Since $\eta(t)$ is arbitrary, we may extract the analogue of the finite case:
$$
\bigg[ \frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial x(t)} - \frac{d}{dt} \frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial \dot{x}(t)} \bigg] _{x _{cl} (t) } = 0 \quad \text{ for } t_i \leq t \leq t_f
$$
This is the famous <strong>Euler Lagrange equation</strong>.</p>
<h2 id="does-this-give-back-nlm">Does this give back NLM?</h2>
<p>If we feed into the equation,
$$
\mathbf{L} = T - V
$$</p>
<p>$$
T = \frac{1}{2} m \dot{x} ^2
$$</p>
<p>$$
V = V(x)
$$</p>
<p>Then we get,
$$
\frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial \dot{x}} = \frac{\partial T}{\partial \dot{x}} = m \dot{x}
$$
and
$$
\frac{\partial \mathbf{L}}{\partial x} = - \frac{\partial V}{\partial x}
$$
and so the Euler-Lagrange equation becomes Newton&rsquo;s Second Law for this case,
$$
\frac{d}{dt} (m \dot{x}) = - \frac{\partial V}{\partial x}
$$
<em>and we are done!</em></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/physics/euler-lagrange/images/doggo.png" type="" alt="doggo"  /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Quiz - 25-03-2023</title>
      <link>https://casiowave.github.io/interests/quiz/tech-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://casiowave.github.io/interests/quiz/tech-quiz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Made in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://students.iiserkol.ac.in/~ar22ms052&#34;&gt;Abhratanu Ray&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://students.iiserkol.ac.in/~ss22ms037&#34;&gt;Sabarno Saha&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very first quiz set we made for the Quiz Club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find it &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vRFgFFV4avSRcDXF9uR7c0bXO-WQulyGEDG1ym_zhiG1mAowBSL4tJDp2TzE3UcOLghAqlP26mDBhFn/embed?start=false&amp;amp;loop=false&amp;amp;delayms=30000&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Made in collaboration with <a href="https://students.iiserkol.ac.in/~ar22ms052">Abhratanu Ray</a> and <a href="https://students.iiserkol.ac.in/~ss22ms037">Sabarno Saha</a>.</p>
<p>The very first quiz set we made for the Quiz Club.</p>
<p>You can find it <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vRFgFFV4avSRcDXF9uR7c0bXO-WQulyGEDG1ym_zhiG1mAowBSL4tJDp2TzE3UcOLghAqlP26mDBhFn/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=30000">here</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War Quiz - 03-11-2023</title>
      <link>https://casiowave.github.io/interests/quiz/war-quiz---03-11-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://casiowave.github.io/interests/quiz/war-quiz---03-11-2023/</guid>
      <description>Wacky wars galore!</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/interests/quiz/war-quiz---03-11-2023/uncle-sam.jpeg" type="" alt="Uncle Sam"  /></p>
<p>A quiz based solely on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/War">wars</a> that I made. You can find it <a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1gf9q-j7L3e9G3P-iCwr2rqCorg5ndJE1ijFdGSK1U1s/edit?usp=sharing">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started!</title>
      <link>https://casiowave.github.io/interests/electronics/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://casiowave.github.io/interests/electronics/get-started/</guid>
      <description>Some guidance for beginners</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/interests/electronics/get-started/images/get-started.gif" type="" alt="get-started"  /></p>
<p>A collection of online (and offline) resources that, in my opinion, are ideal for anyone who wishes to start tinkering. The list is continually being updated as I encounter good resources out there in the wild.</p>
<h1 id="general-websites">General Websites</h1>
<p>Reference for guided tutorials, theory, project ideas, and news pertinent to the hobbyist electronics community.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.electronics-tutorials.ws/">Electronics-Tutorial</a> : Simple, clean tutorial site. The topics are not arranged in an ideal sequence, in my opinion, but it is still a great first reference.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://learn.sparkfun.com/">Sparkfun Learn</a> : A pretty exhaustive list of tutorials (and in general, information) regarding the myriad modules you can get for the Arduino ecosystem.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.allaboutcircuits.com/textbook/">All About Circuits</a> : Framed like a textbook (technically, it <strong>is</strong> one), it is an excellent learning resource for beginners. Their <a href="https://www.allaboutcircuits.com/">blog</a> is pretty technical, but you can find useful/interesting stuff on it.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="http://electronicstheory.com/COURSES/ELECTRONICS/e101-1.htm">electronicstheory.com</a> : A very old, and respected, site on electronics theory up to an intermediate level.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.instructables.com/circuits/">Instructables</a> : Always a good source for project ideas.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.eevblog.com/">EEVblog</a> : Best blog out there for all things EE.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.electrical4u.com/electrical-engineering-articles/digital-electronics/">Electrical4U</a> : Informative articles.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://docs.arduino.cc/learn/">Arduino Docs</a> : Something you should have in your bookmarks if you work with Arduinos. Well written, and concise.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="communities">Communities</h1>
<p>Communities are a great way to get involved with electronics as a hobby.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/AskElectronics/wiki/beginners/">/r/AskElectronics</a> : For those of you out there who are familiar with Reddit, r/AskElectronics is a very good community to get started in.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://electronics.stackexchange.com/">Electronics StackExchange</a> : Ask questions here, if Reddit is not your thing (and I don&rsquo;t blame you if it isn&rsquo;t).</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="video-resources">Video Resources</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLAROrg3NQn7cyu01HpOv5BWo217XWBZu0">GreatScott&rsquo;s Electronic Basics Playlist</a> : If video tutorials are your thing, GreatScott&rsquo;s Electronic Basics is an excellent place to start. You might want to check out his YT Channel in general, it has great stuff.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCosnWgi3eorc1klEQ8pIgJQ">Afrotechmods</a> : Though he hasn&rsquo;t put out any new videos/blog posts in over 5 years, Afrotechmods&rsquo; YT channel and website remain excellent references.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="books">Books</h1>
<p>You&rsquo;ll find me hoarding these books at the Library most of the time, but I&rsquo;m willing to share.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><em>The Art of Electronics</em> - Paul Horowitz, Winfield Hill: Highly recommended read. Our library has a copy, <a href="http://lib.iiserkol.ac.in:8080/lib/item?id=chamo:7869&amp;theme=iiserk">here</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Electronic Principles</em> - Albert Paul Malvino, David J. Bates: Standard textbook on all things electronics - and for good reason. Library copy <a href="http://lib.iiserkol.ac.in:8080/lib/item?id=chamo:808&amp;theme=iiserk">here</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Digital Computer Electronics</em> - Albert Paul Malvino, Jerald A. Brown: Library copy <a href="http://lib.iiserkol.ac.in:8080/lib/item?id=chamo:2121&amp;theme=iiserk">here</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Practical Electronics Handbook</em> - Ian R. Sinclair, John Dunton: The library has a <a href="http://lib.iiserkol.ac.in:8080/lib/item?id=chamo:3362&amp;theme=iiserk">copy</a>, but I haven&rsquo;t been able to track it down yet :(</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><em>Electronics: A Physical Approach</em> - David W. Snoke: Excellent read, also highly recommended.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h1 id="arduino-specific">Arduino specific</h1>
<p>If you ask me, the best way to start is to just get yourself and <a href="https://www.amazon.in/arduino-kit/s?k=arduino&#43;kit">Arduino kit</a>, go on Instructables, decide on some project (doesn&rsquo;t matter if it looks complicated, it just needs to interest you) and, well, <strong>just start</strong>.
In my experience, you always learn this stuff faster if you build it yourself instead of just reading the theory.</p>
<h1 id="more-to-come">More to come!</h1>
<p>I&rsquo;ll be adding websites, YT channels, books, and other resources as I come across them. Feel free to <a href="mailto:ds22ms038@iiserkol.ac.in">contact me</a> with any suggestions!
Looking forward to an active hobbyist electronics community on campus :)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
